Robert Winslow Gordon papers
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Song texts collected by others and acquired by Robert Winslow Gordon, 1922-1932
  - Subseries 8: Howard W. Odum and J.D. Arthur manuscripts, 1929
    Approximately 83 songs contributed by Howard W. Odum of the University of North Carolina in July 1929. Obtained by Odum from J.D. Arthur of Tennessee.
    - Typescripts, 1-83, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/9)
    - Typescript carbons, 1-83, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/10)
    - Carbons, 1-83, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/11)
  - Subseries 9: R.W. Phillips manuscripts, 1924
    Approximately 22 songs contributed by R.W. Phillips of Akeley, Minnesota in March 1924.
    - Original notebook, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/12)
    - Typescripts, 1-22, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/13)
    - Carbons, 1-22, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 23/14)
  - Subseries 10: Betty Bush Winger manuscripts, 1931-1932
    Approximately 125 songs obtained from Betty Bush Winger of Point Pleasant, West Virginia, including traditional African American songs from Winger's home in the Ozark region of Missouri.
    - Originals, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/1)
- Series 4: Inferno collection, circa 1920-1928
  Bawdy songs taken from the Adventure, California, Georgia, and Davids manuscripts and indexed separately.
  - California originals, 239-250, 348, 377-408, circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/2)
  - California typescripts, 239-250, 348, 377-408, circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/3)
  - R.M. Davids typescripts, 1924, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Georgia original and typescript, 560, circa 1926-1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Originals, part 1 (through 1261), circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Originals, part 2 (through 2471), circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Originals, part 3 (through 2789), circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/8)
  - Originals, part 4 (through 3918), circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/9)
  - Typescripts, circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/10)
  - Carbons, circa 1920-1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 24/11)
- Series 5: Published music, 1862-1932
  Published music collected by Robert Winslow Gordon, many of these publications are inscribed to Gordon by the composer.
  - Alphabetical Catalogue of Songs Contained in Delaney's Song Book, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/1)
  - The Ballad of Chevy Chase, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Bayou Ballads, 1921, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/3)
  - Boquet of Comic Songs and Great Mikado folio, 1885, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/4)
  - College Songs, 1887, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Contents of Trifet's Budget of Music, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Delaney's Irish Song Book, Nos. 1-4, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/7)
  - Delaney's Recitations, Nos. 1-3, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/8)
  - Delaney's Recitations, Nos. 4-6, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/9)
  - Delaney's Recitations, Nos. 7-9, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/10)
  - Delaney's Recitations, Nos. 10-11, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 25/11)
  - Delaney's Scotch Song Book, No. 1, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Delaney's Song Book, No. 1, April 1892, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Entertainment and Minstrel Folio, 1925, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Father of the Land We Love, 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/5)
  - W.C. Handy sheet music, 1919-1925, Includes: "Atlanta Blues," 1924; "Blind Man Blues," 1919; "The Chicago Gouge," 1924; "Deep River Blues," 1925; "Famous Comic Blues for the Ukulele," 1925; "The Gouge of Armour Avenue," 1924; "I'm Drinking from a Fountain That Never Runs Dry," 1925; "Joe Turner Blues," 1925; "John Henry Blues," 1922; "Harlem Blues," 1922; "Long Gone," 1920; "Loveless Love," 1921; "The Saint Louis Blues," 1924; "Stingaree Blues," 1924; "The Yellow Dog Blues," 1919.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/6)
    Many of the pieces of sheet music are inscribed by W.C. Handy to Robert Winslow Gordon.
  - Happy Land of Canaan, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Harmonized Melodies No. 34, 1893, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/8)
  - Hawaiian Folio, 1924, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/9)
  - Howe's Eclectic School for the Flute, 1872, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/10)
  - Jubilee and Plantation Songs, 1887, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/11)
  - Mary Earl's Song Book for the Kiddies, 1924, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/12)
  - Miscellaneous song books and title pagers, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/13)
  - Molineaux Collection of Sacred Music for Male Voices, 1888, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/14)
  - Mountain Ballads, 1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/15)
  - Musical Courier, 1932, 1 oversize manuscript (Box-folder OS 1/1)
  - Music from the Days of George Washington, 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/16)
  - The Music for Wakefield: A Folk-Masque, 1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/17)
  - Novelty Blues Song Folio, 1923, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/19)
  - Our College Boys' Songs, 1887, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/20)
  - Over the Hill Songster, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/21)
  - Poems and Songs of California, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/22)
  - Popular Song Classics, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 26/23)
  - Sheet music, B-E, 1921-1925, Includes: "Bye and Bye," 1923; "Dear Heart of Mine," 1924; "Dear Old Southland," 1921; "De Clouds Are Gwine to Roll Away," 1924; "Don't Try to Cry Your Way Back to Me," 1925; "Down Hawaii Way," 1924.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/1)
    Sheet music from various composers collected by Robert Winslow Gordon. Many of the pieces are inscribed by their composer to Gordon.
  - Sheet music, F-H, 1923-1925, Includes: "Frankie and Johnny (You'll Miss Me in the Days to Come)," 1923; "Golden Memories (of Hawaii)," 1925; "Hinky Dinky Parlay Voo?," 1924; "Honolulu Rose," 1924.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Sheet music, I-P, 1923-1925, Includes: "If I Knew, If Only I Knew," 1924; "It Looks Like Rain," 1924; "Just Alone with My Shattered Dreams," 1924; "Lightning Express," 1925; "My Dream Sweetheart," 1923; "Oh Peter (You're So Nice)," 1924; "The Prisoner's Song," 1924.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Sheet music, S-T, 1924-1925, Includes: "Swanee River Dreams," 1924; "Song Birds in Georgia," 1924; "Silver Sands of the Waikiki," 1925; "Stack O'Lee Blues," 1924; "Thunderstorm Blues," 1925.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Sheet music, U-Y, 1922-1925, Includes: "Unexpectedly," 1922; "Whistlin' the Blues Away," 1924; "When It's Love-Time in Hawaii," 1924; "Will You Remember (What I Can't Forget)," 1924; "What-cha-call-'em-Blues," 1925; "Will You Forget Me While I'm Away?," 1924; "Your Eyes," 1924.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. I, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/6)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 68-100, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 101-110, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/8)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 111-120, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/9)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 121-130, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 131-140, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 141-150, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 151-160, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/13)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 161-170, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/14)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 171-180, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/15)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 181-190, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/16)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, No. 188, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/17)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 191-200, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/18)
  - Singer's Journal, Vol. II, Nos. 201, 226-227, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/19)
  - Song Hit Folio No. 3, 1891, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/20)
  - Song Hit Folio fragment, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 27/21)
  - Song Olio, 1883, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/1)
  - Songs for Harvard, Yale, and Princeton Students, 1885, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/2)
  - The Summer Evening Collection of Music, June 1894, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Untitled music book fragment, circa 1886, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/4)
  - Vocal Folio Vol. II, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/5)
  - Wehman Brothers Recitations, Nos. 2, 4, 6, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/6)
  - The Yankee, 1862, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/7)
- Series 6: Published serials, magazines, and reprints, 1840-1932
  Published magazines, serials, and article reprints collected by Robert Winslow Gordon.
  - Ace-High Magazine, November 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Adventure Magazine, 1923-1925, Vol. XLI, 1923. Vol. LV, No. 1, 1925.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 28/9)
  - The American Magazine, February 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/1)
  - The American Mercury, 1928-1930, October 1928 and May 1930 editions.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Army List and Directory, January 1, 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/3)
  - Atlantic Monthly, October 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/4)
  - Phillips Barry, reprints of articles, 1910-1911, 1928, "The Origin of Folk-Melodies," reprinted from The Journal of American Folk-Lore, Vol. 23, October-December, 1910. "Irish Folk-Song," reprinted from The Journal of American Folk-Lore, Vol. 24, No. 92, July-September 1911. "Fair Florella," reprinted from American Speech, Vol. 3, No. 6, August 1928.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Book lists, 1927-1930, "Scottish Books," 1930. "A Second List of Books," The John Day Company, 1927.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Broadsides (1 of 3), circa 1840-1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/7)
  - Broadsides (2 of 3), circa 1840-1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/8)
  - Broadsides (3 of 3), circa 1840-1928, 1 oversize manuscript (Box-folder OS 1/3)
  - Bulletin of the Folk-Song Society of the Northeast, 1931, No. 2 and No. 3.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/9)
  - Bulletin of the New York Public Library, Vol. 28, Nos. 11-12, 1924, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/10)
  - Canadian Folk Song and Handicraft Festival Program, 1927-1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/11)
  - Collier Cobb, An American Man of Letters: George Horton, The Negro Poet, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/12)
  - Concert and performance programs, 1930, "Masque of the Absaroka." Society for the Preservation of Spirituals. Concert of Latin American Music.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 29/13)
  - R.W. Coues, Odd Terms in a Writer of Letters, Dialect Notes, Vol. VI, Part 1, 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/1)
  - Frances Densmore, reprints of articles, 1927-1928, "Some Results of the Study of American Indian Music," reprinted from Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences, Vol. 18, No. 14, August 19, 1928. "The Study of Indian Music in the Nineteenth Century," reprinted from The American Anthropologist, January-March 1927.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/2)
  - Dialect Notes, 1929-1930, Vol. 5, Index and Vol. 6, Part II.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/3)
  - Fischer Edition News, Vol. VI, No. 3, May-July 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Forum, September 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/5)
  - The Golden Book Magazine, May 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/6)
  - Harold Golder, Browning's Childe Roland, 1924, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/7)
  - Harold Golder, Bunyan's Great Despair, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/8)
  - Grosvenor Library Bulletin, 1919-1925, Vol. 1, No. 3. Vol. 5, No. 3. Vol 5, No. 4. Vol 7, No. 3.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/9)
  - Harper's New Monthly Magazine, Vol. LXXIX, No. CCCCLXIX, June 1889, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/10)
  - The Interpreter, November 1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/11)
  - The John Griswold White Collection: Folklore and Orientalia, May 1925, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/12)
  - Journal of the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, Vol. I, No. 2, February 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/13)
  - The Journal of English and Germanic Philology, July 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/14)
  - George Lyman Kittredge, The Ballad of Lovewell's Fight, 1925, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/15)
  - The Library of Congress and its Activities, 1926, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/16)
  - Library of Congress Exhibition of Prints from the Mabel Brady Garvan Institute of American Arts and Crafts at Yale University, Catalogue, 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/17)
  - Library of Congress Reading Rooms: Special Facilities and Regulations for Research, 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 30/18)
  - Library of Congress Special Facilities and Regulations for Research, 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/1)
  - Library of Congress Subject Subdivisions, 6th edition, 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/2)
  - Linguistic Society of America, Bulletin No. 7, March 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/3)
  - The Literary Digest, November 15, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/4)
  - Man, Bird, and Beast: Publications of the Texas Folk-Lore Society, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Anna Blanche McGill, On the Trail of Song Ballets, 1926, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Middleton and Stone, Vol. II, pages 17-32, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/7)
  - Middleton and Stone, Vol. III, pages 33-48, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Ozark Life, Vol. IV, No. 24, May 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 37/1)
  - Ozark Life, Vol. V, No. 1, June 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 37/2)
  - Ozark Life, Vol. V, No. 2, June 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 37/3)
  - Ozark Life, Vol. V, No. 5, August 1929, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 37/4)
  - Ozark Life, 1929-1930, September 1929, October-November 1929, December 1929, January 1930, February 1930, March-April 1930 issues.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/9)
  - Ozark Life,, No. 5, May 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 37/5)
  - Ozark Life, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/10)
  - Haywood Parker, reprints of articles, 1906, "Folklore of the North Carolina Mountaineer," reprinted from The Pen and Plate Club, 1906.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/11)
  - L.W. Payne Jr., reprints of articles, 1926-1930, "Songs and Ballads -- Grave and Gay," reprinted from Texas and Southwestern Lore, No. 6, 1927. "Some Texas Versions of 'The Frog's Courting': The Way of the Folk With a Song," reprinted from Publications of the Texas Folk-Lore Society, No. 5, 1926. "Recent Research in Balladry and Folk Songs," reprinted from Publications of the Texas Folk-Lore Society, Vol. 8, 1930.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/12)
  - The Pelican, February 1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/13)
  - Popular Magazine, 1911, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/14)
  - Popular Magazine, 1916, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 31/15)
  - Popular Magazine, 1919, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 32/1)
  - Popular Magazine, 1920, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 32/2)
  - Popular Magazine, 1922, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 32/3)
  - Radio World, November 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 32/4)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, September 1917, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 32/5)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, February 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/1)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, November 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/3)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/4)
  - Railroad Man's Magazine, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/5)
  - Railroad Stories, August 1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 33/6)
  - The Railway Post Office, Vol. XXXII, No. I, August 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Sea Breezes: The P.S.N.C. Magazine, 1922-1923, Vol. 4, No. 34, Vol. 4, No. 35, Vol. 4, No. 36, Vol. 4, No. 37, Vol. 4, No. 38; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Sea Stories Magazine, 1922, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/3)
  - School and university bulletins, 1931, Phillips Exeter Academy, January 1931. University of South Carolina, March 1931.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Odell Shepard, reprints of articles, 1932, "The American Scholar," reprinted from The American Scholar, Vol. 1, No. 2, March 1931; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Sketch of the Armfield Family, 1902, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/6)
  - Reed Smith, reprints of articles, 1926, "Gullah," reprinted from Bulletin of the University of South Carolina, No. 190, November 1926.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/7)
  - Society of Motion Picture Engineers programs, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/8)
  - W.M. Stone and B. Clay Middleton, Weeds and Flowers: A Collection of Sketches of East Tennessee; its Scenery; Folk Lore and People, 1917, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/9)
  - Boyd B. Stutler, Captain John Brown and Harper's Ferry: The Story of the Raid and the Old Fire Engine House Known as John Brown's Fort, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/10)
  - The Sunday Star Magazine, February 23, 1930, 1 oversize manuscript (Box-folder OS 1/2)
  - W.H. Thomas, Some Current Folk-Songs of the Negro, The Folk-Lore Society of Texas, 1912, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/11)
  - Time Magazine, August 1931, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/12)
  - Time Magazine excerpts, February 24, 1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/13)
  - The Two Hundreth Anniversary of the Birth of George Washington program, 1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/14)
- Series 7: Correspondence and fieldnotes, 1914-1961
  Correspondence to and from Robert Winslow Gordon and assorted fieldnotes written by Gordon over the course of his career.
  - Adventure Magazine correspondence, 1923-1927, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/15)
  - Correspondence, A-B, 1914, 1923-1932, Phillips Barry, Henry Belden, and Ralph Boggs; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/16)
  - Correspondence, C-D, 1926-1932, Richard Chase, June Clark, and Frank Crummet; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 34/17)
  - Correspondence, E, 1926-1932, Carl Engel; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/1)
  - Correspondence, F-G, 1924-1932, Gladys K. Fletcher and Albert Frankenstein; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/2)
  - Correspondence, H-J, 1925-1931, A.P. Hudson and Guy Johnson; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/3)
  - Correspondence, K-M, 1927-1933, George L. Kittredge and George Korson; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Correspondence, N-O, 1920-1932, Mary Newcomb; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Correspondence, P-R, 1926-1930, Lucy Helen Pearson and George Foster Peabody; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/6)
  - Correspondence, S-W, 1927-1931, Speak-O-Phone Corporation, Sigmund Spaeth, Lamar Stringfield, Frances Toor, N. Howard Thorp, and W.H. Thomas; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/7)
  - Ephemera, 1923-1930, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/8)
  - Establishment of the Archive of American Folk Song, 1926-1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Gordon's appointment and dismissal documents, 1932-1933, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/10)
  - Gordon biographical information, 1950-1961, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/11)
  - Inventory of the Archives of American Folk Song, 1931-1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/12)
  - Library of Congress Folk Song Project Proposal, 1930-1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/13)
  - Reports written by Gordon, 1931-1932, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/14)
  - Field notebooks (1 of 3), circa 1920s, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/15)
  - Field notebooks (2 of 3), circa 1920s, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 35/16)
  - Field notebooks (3 of 3), circa 1920s, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 36/1)
  - Fieldnotes from Georgia, 1928, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 36/2)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1923-1928, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 36/3)
  - Scrapbook of song texts from newspaper clippings, undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 36/4)
  - Malcolm W. Vaughan field notebook - Old Southern Slave Songs, circa 1920s, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 36/5)
- Series 8: Card Catalog, undated
  Index of songs in the Robert Winslow Gordon collection. This card catalog was created by Gordon at the end of his career at the Library of Congress.
  - Song index, Aa - By, Approximately 876 cards (Box 38)
  - Song index, Ca - Dz, Approximately 985 cards (Box 39)
  - Song index, Ea - Haz, Approximately 1,058 cards (Box 40)
  - Song index, Hea - Iwa, Approximately 1,022 cards (Box 41)
  - Song index, Iwe - Ky, Approximately 985 cards (Box 42)
  - Song index, La - Ne, Approximately 1,022 cards (Box 43)